<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>mbirkenkamps blog</title>
    <link>https://mbirkenkamp.github.io/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content on mbirkenkamps blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 21 Apr 2023 12:32:57 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://mbirkenkamp.github.io/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>AI Takeover (part 1)</title>
      <link>https://mbirkenkamp.github.io/blog/posts/ai_takeover_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Apr 2023 12:32:57 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mbirkenkamp.github.io/blog/posts/ai_takeover_1/</guid>
      <description>WHUT??? the world (not only the developers) has been introduced to the latest step in AI hype: ChatGPT, it gathered widespread media attention not during its initial release in December 2022 but in the beginning of 2023. After a couple of years where AI and ML Advancements were incremental (but impressive for certain applications), this marked a distinct step for many (including me).
Was this the first time AI made headlines?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Difference Between Junior and Senior Dev</title>
      <link>https://mbirkenkamp.github.io/blog/posts/difference-between-junior-and-senior-dev/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 May 2022 19:14:13 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mbirkenkamp.github.io/blog/posts/difference-between-junior-and-senior-dev/</guid>
      <description>Why do we have roles? People like naming things Upside It is easier to talk about categories or job levels then to always declare the full function or expertise of a person or group, i.e. &amp;ldquo;That task can be handled by one of the junior devs&amp;rdquo; vs. &amp;ldquo;That task can be handled by one of the devs that know our architecture, but are not yet experienced in the front end code&amp;rdquo;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vue Focus Handling</title>
      <link>https://mbirkenkamp.github.io/blog/posts/vue-focus-handling/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Apr 2022 19:02:22 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mbirkenkamp.github.io/blog/posts/vue-focus-handling/</guid>
      <description>Storytime i was working on a POC for multi factor authentication using time-based one time passwords (TOTP) and wanted to create a nice input UI for this, so i thought this would be a great way to practice my vue knowledge and create another showcase of vue for the team.
What i wanted was a UI like the one iOS uses, so 6 separate input boxes that are more or less handled like a normal input field but pretty 😊.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blog Start</title>
      <link>https://mbirkenkamp.github.io/blog/posts/blog-install/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Apr 2022 21:08:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mbirkenkamp.github.io/blog/posts/blog-install/</guid>
      <description>Why? it all started with the blog post 8 Reasons Why You Should Blog as a Developer and especially the point about communicating clearly, which is becoming more and more important to me as my role shifts from &amp;ldquo;doer&amp;rdquo; to &amp;ldquo;enabler&amp;rdquo;. So it is more important to effectivly instruct others then doing stuff myself.
Additionally i wanted to explore static site generators, so this was the perfect way to do this.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://mbirkenkamp.github.io/blog/posts/challenge_2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mbirkenkamp.github.io/blog/posts/challenge_2023/</guid>
      <description>title: &amp;#34;Challenge 2023&amp;#34; date: 2023-02-16T21:08:00+02:00 tags: [&amp;#34;challenge&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;blog&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;getting shit together&amp;#34;] Why? It has been a loooong time since i last finished a post to my little blog. This is enough to think about the reasons why i wanted to start writing more. Those things still remain the same, so it all comes down to really doing what i wanted to do (aka the hardest part). So I&amp;rsquo;ll try to challenge myself to write a small amount of posts this year, and see if i can at least get this done.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
